Nelly Goletti Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Nelly Goletti Papers
circa 1918 – 1995
NPkMC-222-217
18 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Marist College
The Nelly Goletti Collection documents portions of the career of the popular and classical composer, performer and pianist. Born in Algiers, North Africa, Goletti was considered a child prodigy by the age of six. She completed her musical education by the age of fourteen and went on to become a popular and critically acclaimed composer and performer throughout Europe and the United States.Included in this collection is the music for many of the over 300 songs and compositions by Goletti. Also included are sound recordings, photographs and newspaper clippings.
Collection Overview
The Nelly Goletti Collection consists of sheet music, scores, lyrics, musical sketches, sound recordings, photographs, portraits and newspaper clippings. The collection includes materials primarily from the latter portion of the 20th century.
Acquisitions Information
The Nelly Goletti Collection was presented to the Marist College Library by the Fusco Family.
Historical Note
Nelly Goletti, French chanteuse, composer, and pianist was born in Algiers, North Africa on December 25, 1908. Goletti began studying piano at the age of five and enrolled in the Beaux Arts Conservatory at the age of six. At the age of six she gave her first concert and was recognized from then on as a child prodigy. At the age of thirteen she became the youngest member of S.A.C.E.M., the French society of composers. By the age of fourteen she had completed her studies at Conservatories of Classical Music in Milan and Paris, where she was honored with fourteen first prizes. A student of the world renowned Isadore Phillip, her mark remains at the Paris Conservatory, where her piano etudes are still taught. At the age of sixteen she became the youngest member of the Society of Authors and Composers.
Goletti performed extensively in well-known clubs and cabarets throughout Europe and the United States, including London’s Bagatelle Club in Mayfair. She composed the music to the state musical "Talleyrand" by Sacha Guitry and the complete score for the Casino de Paris. Her songs have been sung by Jean Sablon, Jean Lumiere, Guy Berri, Reda Caire, and others. She has appeared on every major radio network in Europe from Luxemburg to Monte Carlo. In 1947 she was acclaimed as a "female Rachmanioff" by the Ce Soir critic Jean Weiner after a concert at Salle Pleyel. Her two American films performances include "One Too Many" and "The Best is Yet to Come". She became the musical director of Hallmark Productions in Hollywood and she wrote the music for the film "Rich, Young and Pretty", starring Jane Powell. While living in New York she had her own fifteen minute prime time program on WOR-TV every Thursday evening from 7:00 to 7:15 PM. She also appeared on the Steve Allen Show and in Hollywood on Peter Potter’s show.
Nelly Goletti has over three hundred songs and compositions to her name. Her first major song was called "Serenade", other songs were written specifically for music stars like Jean Sablon and Tino Rossi. Her recordings, mainly done in Paris, were on the Decca, Pacific, Columbia and Pathe labels. She was a long-time staff artist at the Paris studios of Decca. Her works, both in the popular and classical musical idioms, have been performed extensively in Europe and the United States. Nelly Goletti’s style as a composer and pianist can be recognized by her unusual harmonies, contrapuntal treatment, beautiful tones and strong attack.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Materials are arranged into twenty series: 1) Lyrics and music by Nelly Goletti, 2) Music by Nelly Goletti (no lyrics), 3) Lyrics by other lyricists, 4) Collective works by Nelly Goletti, 5) Lyrical interpretations by Nelly Goletti, 6) Arrangements by Nelly Goletti, 7) Special Arranements, 8) Works Arranged by Eddie Sauter, 9) Marcel Valenve, 10) Copyrighs and Royalties, 11) Sketches, 12) Photographs, 13) Newspaper clippings, 14) Professional papers, 15) Personal papers, n16) Hanfwritten songs by other composers, 17) Practice books, 18) Audio collection, 19) Audio - Original form, and 20) Cassettes
Materials are arranged alphabetically
- 1. Lyrics and Music by Nelly Goletti, 1; Box: 1 Folders: 1 - 15
  Alphabetical by title
  - Canzone (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Chili Bomba (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Coeur a Prender (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Dans la Clarte du Jour (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Douce Si Donce (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - L'amour Contrarie (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - La Baleine (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - La Foire de S (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Mes Reves (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Poeme Triste a Maria (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Si vous M'Aimiez (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - Taratata! (Folder 12, Box 1)
  - Un Homme! (Folder 13, Box 1)
  - Venez C'est le Printemps! (Folder 14, Box 1)
  - Vous que Jamie en Silence (Folder 15, Box 1)
- 2. Music by Nelly Goletti (no lyrics), 2; Box: 2 Folders: 16 - 66
  - Ali Pacha (Folder 16, Box 2)
  - "L' Alleyrand" oi Le Diable Boiseux (Folder 17, Box 2)
  - Around the World (Folder 18, Box 2)
  - Avec... (Folder 19, Box 2)
  - Un Beau Jour (Folder 20, Box 2)
  - Blanche et Bleu (Folder 21, Box 2)
  - C'est Toujours Ta Chanson (Folder 22, Box 2)
  - Ce Tribunal (Folder 23, Box 2)
  - Christmas Song (Folder 24, Box 2)
  - Claquettes (Folder 25, Box 2)
  - Dance (Folder 26, Box 2)
  - Danseuse Ax Crotales (Folder 27, Box 2)
  - La Flute de Pan (Folder 28, Box 2)
  - Georga (Folder 29, Box 2)
  - Hot Stomp (Folder 30, Box 2)
  - I'll Order a Dream (Folder 31, Box 2)
  - Ils Vont Reveuir les Baux Jours (Folder 32, Box 2)
  - In My Garden (Folder 33, Box 2)
  - Les Jeax (Folder 34, Box 2)
  - Legende (Folder 35, Box 2)
  - Le Long de la Riviere (Folder 36, Box 2)
  - Lovely (Folder 37, Box 2)
  - Lullaby (Folder 38, Box 2)
  - Mais... (Folder 39, Box 2)
  - Marche du "Fancons Ranges" (Folder 40, Box 2)
  - The Merry-Go-Round (Tournez, tournes, cheuax de bois!) (Folder 41, Box 2)
  - Mon Coeus Pres de Toi (Folder 42, Box 2)
  - Monsieur (Folder 43, Box 2)
  - Moon Love (Folder 44, Box 2)
  - Nocturne (Folder 45, Box 2)
  - Nostalgie (Folder 46, Box 2)
  - Les Oiseaux Sur L'Ocean (Folder 47, Box 2)
  - One Note Sonata (Folder 48, Box 2)
  - Passion (Folder 49, Box 2)
  - Petite Valse (Folder 50, Box 2)
  - Prelude (Folder 51, Box 2)
  - Pour Sabrina, Affectueusement (Folder 52, Box 2)
  - Qu'est ce Que Ca Fait (Folder 53, Box 2)
  - Rengaine (Folder 54, Box 2)
  - Le Rossignol (Folder 55, Box 2)
  - Les Roubaiats (Folder 56, Box 2)
  - St Louis Blues (Folder 57, Box 2)
  - Sana Papa, Sana Mamay (Folder 58, Box 2)
  - La Source (Folder 59, Box 2)
  - Souvenir (Folder 60, Box 2)
  - Le Suisse du Village (Folder 61, Box 2)
  - Sur Un Navire Etrange (Folder 62, Box 2)
  - Le Vieux Chameau (Folder 63, Box 2)
  - Waldteufelade (Folder 64, Box 2)
  - Western Suite (Folder 65, Box 2)
  - Misc. Unititled (Folder 66, Box 2)
- 3. Lyrics by Other Lyricists, 3; Boxes: 3 - 7 Folders: 67 - 167
  Alphabetical by Lyricist (Songs with multiple lyricists come at the end)
  - Je Ne Sais Rien de Vous - Max Blot (Folder 67, Box 3)
  - Pour vofre Sourire - Pierre Le Bugulier (Folder 68, Box 3)
  - Le Grande Reale -Raymond Cavanelle (Folder 69, Box 3)
  - Les plus Belles Amours... -Raymond Cavanelle (Folder 70, Box 3)
  - Les Toits Mousus - Raymond Cavanelle (Folder 71, Box 3)
  - Rendez-Vous - Raymond Cavanelle (Folder 72, Box 3)
  - I Will Always Adore You - Don Canoton (Folder 73, Box 3)
  - Shadows on the River - Don Canton (Folder 74, Box 3)
  - The Waltz of the Roses - Don Canton (Folder 75, Box 3)
  - Voici des Fleurs - Henry Cor (Folder 76, Box 3)
  - Rein Dans Les Mains: Rein Dans les Poches - Freddy Daniel (Folder 77, Box 3)
  - Chante Cigale!... -Suzette Desty (Folder 78, Box 3)
  - Le Train Du Bonheur - Suzette Desty (Folder 79, Box 3)
  - C'est de la que Vient ma Peine - M.G. Dorian (Folder 80, Box 3)
  - Comme un Disque d'argent - M.G. Dorian (Folder 81, Box 3)
  - Jeux d'ombres (Folder 82, Box 3)
  - Le Cloitre - M.G. Dorian (Folder 83, Box 3)
  - Les Heures Mortes - M.G. Dorian (Folder 84, Box 3)
  - Penchee sur la Berge - M.G. Dorian (Folder 85, Box 3)
  - Hey, Boy! - David Eddy (Folder 86, Box 3)
  - Dans un Joli Coin de France - Gabriello (Folder 87, Box 3)
  - Qui m'aurait dit ?... -Gabriello (Folder 88, Box 3)
  - Tu M'Impressionnes... - Gabriello (Folder 89, Box 3)
  - Waltz of the Gods (Folder 90, Box 4)
  - Wedding Waltz - Richard Harvey (Folder 91, Box 4)
  - Ametuere - Jacobs (Folder 92, Box 4)
  - Biguine de Riche - Jamblan (Folder 93, Box 4)
  - C'est Toujours Ta Chnanson - L.D. Kerambrun (Folder 94, Box 4)
  - Du Pied Sous la Table - L.D. Kerambrun (Folder 95, Box 4)
  - L'Auberge d Gouhon Qui Rit - L.D. Kerambrun (Folder 96, Box 4)
  - Serenade Florentine - Jean Lahor (Folder 97, Box 4)
  - Il a Meige sur tes Mensonges - Andre Ledur (Folder 98, Box 4)
  - L'Armada - Andre Ledur (Folder 99, Box 4)
  - Mains Calines - Andre Ledur (Folder 100, Box 4)
  - Quatre Roses - Andre Ledur (Folder 101, Box 4)
  - Sur Le Pas De Ta Porte - Andre Ledur (Folder 102, Box 4)
  - Un Gant, Une Robe, Un Chapeau - Andre Ledur (Folder 103, Box 4)
  - Un Jour Etaient Quarte Gareous - Andre Ledur (Folder 104, Box 4)
  - Vielle Legende - Andre Ledur (Folder 105, Box 4)
  - The Cockney Ragtime Band - Bunny Lewis (Folder 106, Box 4)
  - Happy Pedro - Bunny Lewis (Folder 107, Box 4)
  - How Long - Bunny Lewis (Folder 108, Box 4)
  - All in All - Sherman Lippman (Folder 109, Box 4)
  - The Cocoanut Bush - Sherman Lippman (Folder 110, Box 4)
  - The Game of Hearts - Sherman Lippman (Folder 111, Box 4)
  - Gratitude - Sherman Lippman (Folder 112, Box 4)
  - Hush - Sherman Lippman (Folder 113, Box 4)
  - One Day - Sherman Lippman (Folder 114, Box 4)
  - Sycamore Trees - Sherman Lippman (Folder 115, Box 4)
  - Tell Me, Corinna - Sherman Lippman (Folder 116, Box 5)
  - Who Can Say? - Sherman Lippman (Folder 117, Box 5)
  - Will You Shed a Bitter Tear When I Die - Sherman Lippman (Folder 118, Box 5)
  - Untitled - Sherman Lippman (Folder 119, Box 5)
  - Untitled - Sherman Lippman (Folder 120, Box 5)
  - La Poupee de Cire - Jean Moarsary (Folder 121, Box 5)
  - Confidence a la Lune - Gine Money (Folder 122, Box 5)
  - Dans Le Noir - Gine Money (Folder 123, Box 5)
  - Le Plus Bel Amour - Gine Money (Folder 124, Box 5)
  - Patrons en Amouzeux - Gine Money (Folder 125, Box 5)
  - Ah! Mes Amours - France Mortagne (Folder 126, Box 5)
  - Cochonailles - France Mortagne (Folder 127, Box 5)
  - Copain... Always - France Mortagne (Folder 128, Box 5)
  - Danse et vire, mon Navire - France Mortagne (Folder 129, Box 5)
  - Dialogue Feminin - France Mortagne (Folder 130, Box 5)
  - Jeux - France Mortagne (Folder 131, Box 5)
  - Le Bonheur est Toujours en Face - France Mortagne (Folder 132, Box 5)
  - Mon Navire Qui Danse et Vire - France Mortagne (Folder 133, Box 5)
  - Partir.. Qublier tes Blasphemes - France Mortagne (Folder 134, Box 5)
  - Segere les Vertus - France Mortagne (Folder 135, Box 5)
  - Un Printemps Chante en Moi - France Mortagne (Folder 136, Box 5)
  - Untitled - Henry Onorati (Folder 137, Box 5)
  - Complainte [Mes Amours] - Ramuz (Folder 138, Box 5)
  - Feuilles Mortes - Tristan Richepin (Folder 139, Box 5)
  - Intimite - Tristan Richepin (Folder 140, Box 5)
  - L'Orpheon Qui Defile - Tristan Richepin (Folder 141, Box 6)
  - La Chanson de mon Coeur: Tango - Tristan Richepin (Folder 142, Box 6)
  - Le Petite Prison - Tristan Richepin (Folder 143, Box 6)
  - Le Mot Qu'il ne Faut Pas - Tristan Richepin (Folder 144, Box 6)
  - Le Petite Bateau Qui Penche - Tristan Richepin (Folder 145, Box 6)
  - Le Tambour et la Cantiniere - Tristan Richepin (Folder 146, Box 6)
  - Manjana - Tristan Richepin (Folder 147, Box 6)
  - Ne le Reveillez Pas - Tristan Richepin (Folder 148, Box 6)
  - Ritoumelle D'Amour - Tristan Richepin (Folder 149, Box 6)
  - Serenade de la Nuit - Tristan Richepin (Folder 150, Box 6)
  - Un Air de Musette - Tristan Richepin (Folder 151, Box 6)
  - Je L'Attends - Louis Sauvat (Folder 152, Box 6)
  - Peace is Everywhere - John Stephens (Folder 153, Box 6)
  - Buvons, Buvons un Coup! - Simon Vallalle (Folder 154, Box 7)
  - Adieu - Max Viterbo (Folder 155, Box 7)
  - Apres ma Mort - Max Viterbo (Folder 156, Box 7)
  - J'Amimais - Max Viterbo (Folder 157, Box 7)
  - Le Cheval du Cosaque - Max Viterbo (Folder 158, Box 7)
  - Penelope - Max Viterbo (Folder 159, Box 7)
  - Tu Vois Du Mal Partout - Max Viterbo (Folder 160, Box 7)
  - Scherzo - Elise Vollene (Folder 161, Box 7)
  - Cela Ne M'Arrive Qu'n Reve - Jac Zym (Folder 162, Box 7)
  - Une Chaumiere et Votre Coeur - Jac Zym (Folder 163, Box 7)
  - Le Premier Pas - Max Blot and Suzette Desty (Folder 164, Box 7)
  - Quand on a le Dans les Voiles - Tristan Richepin and Geo Bonnet (Folder 165, Box 7)
  - Voici le Film - d'Henry Cor and Jac Zym (Folder 166, Box 7)
  - Jamais Deux sans Trois - Tristan Richepin and Jac Zym (Folder 167, Box 7)
- 4. Collective Works by Nelly Goletti, 4; Boxes: 8 - 10 Folders: 168 - 193
  - Acte I (Folder 168, Box 8)
  - Acte II (Folder 169, Box 8)
  - Acte I Recopie (Folder 170, Box 8)
  - Acte II Recopie (Folder 171, Box 8)
  - Arrangements (Figaro and Carmen) (Folder 172, Box 8)
  - Arrangements for Pianist Extraordinaire (Folder 173, Box 8)
  - Arrangements for Trio (Folder 174, Box 8)
  - Children's Music (Folder 175, Box 8)
  - Chansons en Francais (Folder 176, Box 8)
  - Compulsion (Folder 177, Box 8)
  - 1st Concerto (Folder 178, Box 9)
  - 2eme Concerto (Folder 179, Box 9)
  - Concerto en re (Folder 180, Box 9)
  - Editions de l'Opera: Amour Printanier (Folder 181, Box 9)
  - Editions de L'Opera: Crepuscule D'Amour (Folder 182, Box 9)
  - Editions de L'Opera: Le Lond De 'Etang (Folder 183, Box 9)
  - Histories de la France (Folder 184, Box 9)
  - In a Venitian Gondola (Folder 185, Box 9)
  - La Porte d'or (Ballet) (Folder 186, Box 9)
  - Little Christmas Tree [Christmas Songs] (Folder 187, Box 9)
  - Lyrics Only [Various Lyrics] (Folder 188, Box 10)
  - Maid Marion (Folder 189, Box 10)
  - Merry Go Round (Folder 190, Box 10)
  - Minouche (Folder 191, Box 10)
  - "More Nelly Goletti Music" (Folder 192, Box 10)
  - Suite de Ballet (Folder 193, Box 10)
- 5. Lyrical Interpretations by Nelly Goletti, circa 1918 – 1995; 5; Box: 11 Folders: 194 - 195
  Alphabetical by Subject.
  - Drafts of Lyrics (Notebook) (Folder 194, Box 11)
  - Paris (from Rich, Young and Pretty) (Folder 195, Box 11)
- 6. Arrangements by Nelly Goletti, 6; Box: 12 Folders: 196 - 220
  Alphabetical by composer
  - Seul Sur Etoile - Be Caud (Folder 196, Box 12)
  - C'est Si Bon - Betti (Folder 197, Box 12)
  - Prince Igor - Borodin (Folder 198, Box 12)
  - Clopin-Clopani - Dudan (Folder 199, Box 12)
  - Sophisticated Lady Nelly Golette (Folder 200, Box 12)
  - Caberet - Kander (Folder 201, Box 12)
  - Autumn Leaves - Kosma (Folder 202, Box 12)
  - Liebestaum - F. Liszt (Folder 203, Box 12)
  - Le Vie En Rose - Louiguy (Folder 204, Box 12)
  - And I Love You So - McLean (Folder 205, Box 12)
  - Concerto No. 2 - Rachmanionoff (Folder 206, Box 12)
  - Il Pleut Bergere - Victor Simon (Folder 207, Box 12)
  - Romeo and Juliet - P. Tchaikovsky (Folder 208, Box 12)
  - Song of India - Rimsky-Korsakov (Folder 209, Box 12)
  - Melody - Rubinstein (Folder 210, Box 12)
  - Mon Homme - Yuain (Folder 211, Box 12)
  - Unknown Composers: (Box 12)
  - Doina (Folder 212, Box 12)
  - Hora Staccato (Folder 213, Box 12)
  - I Know What You Know (Folder 214, Box 12)
  - I Wish You Love (Folder 215, Box 12)
  - La Seine (Folder 216, Box 12)
  - Partons en Amoureux (Folder 217, Box 12)
  - Rapsody in Blue (Folder 218, Box 12)
  - Ritournelle D'Amour (Folder 219, Box 12)
  - Row Row Row (Folder 220, Box 12)
- 7. Special Arrangements, 7; Box: 13 Folders: 221 - 254
  By instrument
  - Instrument: Remo (Box 13)
    - I Wish You Love (Folder 221, Box 13)
    - C'est Si Bon (Folder 222, Box 13)
    - Row, Row, Row (Folder 223, Box 13)
    - Romance (Folder 224, Box 13)
    - Song of India (Folder 225, Box 13)
    - La Vie en Rose (Folder 226, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Drums (Box 13)
    - Row, Row, Row (Folder 227, Box 13)
    - C'Est Si Bon (Folder 228, Box 13)
    - Prince Igor Bordin (Folder 229, Box 13)
    - Romance Tschaikowsky (Folder 230, Box 13)
    - Song of India (Folder 231, Box 13)
    - Stormy Weather - Night and Day (Folder 232, Box 13)
    - Tea for Two (Folder 233, Box 13)
    - La Vie En Rose (Folder 234, Box 13)
    - I Wish You Love (Folder 235, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Guitar (Box 13)
    - Prince Igor (Folder 236, Box 13)
    - Stormy Weather - Night and Day (Folder 237, Box 13)
    - Two Guitars P.D. (Folder 238, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Bass (Box 13)
    - Monsieur (Folder 239, Box 13)
    - Sophisticated Lady (Folder 240, Box 13)
    - Tea for Two (Folder 241, Box 13)
    - Foxtrot (Published Arrangement) (Folder 242, Box 13)
    - Syncopated Clock (Published Arrangement) (Folder 243, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Saxophone (Box 13)
    - Foxtrot (Published Arrangement) (Folder 244, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Violin (Box 13)
    - C'est Si Bon (Folder 245, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Full Arrangement (Box 13)
    - Melody No. 2 Chopin Clopant (Folder 246, Box 13)
    - Polonaise (Folder 247, Box 13)
  - Instrument: Misc. (Box 13)
    - Dorena (Folder 248, Box 13)
    - La Fiacle (Folder 249, Box 13)
    - A Pied (Folder 250, Box 13)
    - Stormy Weather - Night and Day (Folder 251, Box 13)
    - Romance - Tschaikowsky (Folder 252, Box 13)
    - Impromptu - Chopin (Folder 253, Box 13)
    - Sabre Dance - Khatchaturyan (Folder 254, Box 13)
- 8. Works Arranged by Eddie Sauter, 8; Boxes: 14 - 15 Folders: 255 - 262
  Alphabetical
  - April in Paris (Folder 255, Box 14)
  - Autumn Leaves (Folder 256, Box 14)
  - I Love Paris (Folder 257, Box 14)
  - I Wish You Love (Folder 258, Box 14)
  - La Seine (Folder 259, Box 14)
  - Mes Amours (Folder 260, Box 15)
  - Souvenir (Folder 261, Box 15)
  - Ta Chanson (Folder 262, Box 15)
- 9. Marcel Valence, 9; Box: 16 Folders: 263 - 283
  Series contains there are some indications that the compositions in this series were either arranged by Nelly Goletti or Marcel Valance was a psuedonym used by Nelly Goletti.
  The current arrangement reflects how the collection was originally processed, there appears to be no specific method to how files were arranged within the box.
  - Italia (Folder 263, Box 16)
  - Lily (Folder 264, Box 16)
  - Miami (Foxtrot) (Folder 265, Box 16)
  - Si. Oui Yes. You (Folder 266, Box 16)
  - La Trompette Ivre (She Drunk Trumpet) (Folder 267, Box 16)
  - Me or en Cruil Rien (Folder 268, Box 16)
  - Love Barytou (Folder 269, Box 16)
  - Boston: Marina (Folder 270, Box 16)
  - Louisiana (Folder 271, Box 16)
  - Salamanca (Folder 272, Box 16)
  - El Papagallo (Folder 273, Box 16)
  - Fly (Folder 274, Box 16)
  - Fox Blues: River Black (Folder 275, Box 16)
  - Love me (Folder 276, Box 16)
  - Who me? (Folder 277, Box 16)
  - New Blues (Folder 278, Box 16)
  - Nostalgie (Folder 279, Box 16)
  - Europea Symphonic No. 1 Lojoden (Folder 280, Box 16)
  - Europea Symphonic No. 2 Rococonibus (Folder 281, Box 16)
  - Europea Symphonic No. 3 Le Steppe (Folder 282, Box 16)
  - Europea Symphonic No. 4 Balaivin (Folder 283, Box 16)
- 10. Copyrights and Royalties, 10; Boxes: 16 - 17 Folders: 284 - 298
  - AH, Mes Amours (Folder 284, Box 16)
  - C'est Toujours ta Chanson (Folder 285, Box 16)
  - La Chasse ala Baleine (Folder 286, Box 16)
  - La Flute de Pan (Folder 287, Box 16)
  - Le Porte D'or (Synopsis of the Ballet) (Folder 288, Box 16)
  - Nelly Goletti Pianist Extraordinaire (Folder 289, Box 17)
  - Prelude (Folder 290, Box 17)
  - Souvenir (Folder 291, Box 17)
  - The Little Christmas Tree (Folder 292, Box 17)
  - Whispering Trees (Folder 293, Box 17)
  - Royalties - ASCAP (Folder 294, Box 17)
  - Royalties-SACEM 1927-1937 (Folder 295, Box 17)
  - Royalties-SACEM through 1938 (Folder 296, Box 17)
  - Royalties-SACEM-Agreement and Policy (Folder 297, Box 17)
  - Royalties - Waltz of Roses (Folder 298, Box 17)
- 11. Sketches, 11; Box: 18 Folders: 299 - 303
  Series contains outlines for acts that were to appear on Nelly Goletti’s show or for acts that she would be performing on other shows. Sketches are both handwritten and typed. The materials are not dated.
  - Photocopied Sketches in Binder (Folder 299, Box 18)
  - Signed Sheet Music by Nelly Goletti (Folder 300, Box 18)
  - Unsigned Sheet Music (Folder 301, Box 18)
  - Multiple sketches on one sheet (Folder 302, Box 18)
  - Red Folder (Created by Nelly Goletti) (Folder 303, Box 18)
- 12. Photographs, 12; Boxes: 19 - 20 Folders: 304 - 327
  Series depicts both Nelly Goletti’s professional and private life. The majority of pictures are professional done by photography studios but amateur photos of family and friends are also included. Along with the photographs, there are a few slides that are included in the family photos file. While the majority of photographs depict Goletti’s career from the age of 20 to 45, a limited number show her early childhood as well as later in life. The majority of images are not dated.
  Arrangemnt: Chronologically arranged by age and then switched to alphabetical by subject.
  - Age 20 (Folder 304, Box 19)
  - Age 25 (Folder 305, Box 19)
  - Age 30 (Folder 306, Box 19)
  - Age 35 (Folder 307, Box 19)
  - Age 40 (Folder 308, Box 19)
  - Age 45 (Folder 309, Box 19)
  - Childhood Photos (Folder 310, Box 19)
  - Damaged Photos (Folder 311, Box 19)
  - Family Photos (Folder 312, Box 19)
  - Funeral Photo Handouts (Folder 313, Box 19)
  - Fusco Culinary Event (Folder 314, Box 19)
  - Hallmark Production Inc. (Folder 315, Box 19)
  - Kehren Studio (Paris) (Folder 316, Box 19)
  - James J. Kriegsmann Studio (Folder 317, Box 19)
  - Leon Austern Studio (Folder 318, Box 19)
  - Middlesex County Times and West Middles Gazette (Folder 319, Box 19)
  - Misc. (Folder 320, Box 19)
  - Misc. Headshots (Folder 321, Box 19)
  - Negatives of the Riverside Drive Home (Folder 322, Box 19)
  - Paintings of Nelly Goletti (Folder 323, Box 20)
  - Performance Photos (Folder 324, Box 20)
  - Photographic Album (See Oversized 1) (Folder 325, Box 20)
  - Ship's Lantern Performance (Folder 326, Box 20)
  - White House Visit (Includes photos of Nelly Goletti and Ronald Reagan) (Folder 327, Box 20)
- 13. Newspaper Clippings, 13; Box: 20 Folders: 328 – 340
  - 1950 (Folder 328, Box 20)
  - 1951 (Folder 329, Box 20)
  - 1952 (Folder 330, Box 20)
  - 1953 (Folder 331, Box 20)
  - 1954 (Folder 332, Box 20)
  - 1957-1958 (Folder 333, Box 20)
  - 1960s (Folder 334, Box 20)
  - 1970s (Folder 335, Box 20)
  - 1980s-1990s (Folder 336, Box 20)
  - Undated (Folder 337, Box 20)
  - Advertisements (Folder 338, Box 20)
  - Dedicating the Milton Burle Room; Clubhouse (Folder 339, Box 20)
  - Paris Match (Folder 340, Box 20)
- 14. Professional Papers, 14; Boxes: 20 - 21 Folders: 341- 361
  Series contains Nelly Goletti’s professional papers reflect performances, television shows, and radio shows that she a star in. This series covers her career from the 1940s through the 1990s with the majority of items being from the 1950s. The bulk of papers are advertisements or pamphlets for her performances but press releases, reviews, and scripts are also included.
  - Lyrics (Handwritten and Typed) (Folder 341, Box 20)
  - Misc. (Folder 342, Box 20)
  - Misc. Letters (Folder 343, Box 20)
  - Performance Pamphlets (Folder 344, Box 21)
  - Playlists (Handwritten and Typed) (Folder 345, Box 21)
  - Press Releases (Folder 346, Box 21)
  - Programs - 1950 (Folder 347, Box 21)
  - Programs - 1952 (Folder 348, Box 21)
  - Programs - 1958 (Folder 349, Box 21)
  - Programs - 1977 (Folder 350, Box 21)
  - Programs - 1984 (Folder 351, Box 21)